digitallocker.gov.in 2019-12-13

# DigiLocker | Privacy Policy

Last Modified: March 14, 2017

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) is in the context of and to govern the access and usage of the DigiLocker System application and DigiLocker Portal/website an initiative of MeitY (Ministry of Electronics & Information Technology), Government of India. 

This Privacy Policy describes and determines how DigiLocker application (referred to as MeitY or We/Us or DigiLocker System or DigiLocker Account holder), handle and/ or deal with your (referred to as You or User) personal and usage information, in accordance with the applicable laws of India. 

This Privacy Policy is liable to change without notice at the discretion of the Ministry of Electronics & Information Technology, Government of India. Any change in the Privacy policy will be notified to all the DigiLocker Account holders.

The Privacy Policy for the DigiLocker System as described below has been kept as simple as possible and provides the details of personal and usage information as collected from the user. In case the user is not familiar with certain technical terms he/she is advised to read the key terms first and in case doubt still persist he/ she may write to us at _support[at]digitallocker[dot]gov[dot]in_. 

  1. The DigiLocker System allows the user to browse the site without signing up. In this case it will not capture any specific personal information about the user (for example name, phone number, email ID) that may not allow us to identify anyone individually. 
  2. In case the user wishes to sign up for DigiLocker Account, the user must provide his/her personal mobile number. Subsequently the user may link their account with Aadhaar number for the purpose of authentication. As part of the Aadhaar authentication, eKYC details of the user are collected and associated with DigiLocker account.
  3. The issuers of the DigiLocker System may push the documents or certificates to user’s DigiLocker account in electronic form or through a Uniform Resource Identifier (URI). 
  4. The DigiLocker System allows the holder of account to digitally (electronically) sign using the service of a licensed eSign Service Provider and self upload documents free of charge.
  5. DigiLocker Portal collects information such as Internet Protocol (IP) Addresses, Domain name, Browser type, Operating System, Date and Time of the visit, Pages visited, Referring URLs etc. However no attempt is being made to link these with the identity of individuals visiting the DigiLocker Portal unless an unlawful attempt to violate/infringe the DigiLocker service and privacy policy or provisions of the Information Technology Act, 2000 or under any law for the time being in force has been detected.
  6. The DigiLocker System uses cookies and these cookies are used to record current session information to improve the user experience of DigiLocker and to tailor it to his/ her preference. However no permanent cookies are used. Further the user can control the cookies through his browser settings and use of other tools. The blocking of cookies may however result in non continuance of the DigiLocker Session. The users are well advised to close their sessions after use so as to avoid possible misuse of cookies information. 
  7. The DigiLocker System does not share/ disclose any information including eKYC details of the user collected from Aadhaar at the time of sign up with any individual or Organization (public or private) unless and until it is required by law or it is authorized by the account holder with his/her consent.
  8. The DigiLocker Account holder will be at liberty to share his/ her uploaded documents or URIs to any individual or Organization at his/her own accord and free will by providing his/her express consent. The responsibility of sharing of documents with requesters or other entities lies with the user only as DigiLocker system merely facilitates the sharing of documents.
  9. As far as transparency and choice is concerned the DigiLocker System allows the user to see and analyze the activity log of any document or URI shared by him/ her with various individuals and the Organizations. 
  10. The DigiLocker account holder is solely responsible for all the self uploaded documents. At no point of time the account holder is allowed to share or perform any act which may be in violation of the terms and conditions of DigiLocker service, privacy policy or provisions of the Information Technology Act, 2000 or any other law for the time being in force.
  11. The personal and usage information, as collected may be shared with other Organizations, if Ministry of Electronics and Information Technology have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of the information is reasonably necessary to: 
    * Meet any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable Government request;
    * Detect, prevent or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues as well as investigation of potential violations;
    * Protect against harm to the rights, property or safety of DigiLocker System, other users or the public as required or permitted by law.
  12. In case the Ministry of Electronics & Information Technology, Government of India at some point of time decides to license other public or private Digital Locker Service providers to provide a similar Digital Locker service, it will be ensured that the confidentiality of personal and usage information is maintained in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy, the Information Technology Act, 2000 and Rules made thereunder or any other law for the time being in force.
  13. We do not sell or share any personally identifiable information submitted on the DigiLocker Portal/Website to any third party (public/private), except under the conditions as mentioned above. Any such information provided to this website will be reasonably protected from loss, misuse, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration, or destruction.
  14. The DigiLocker System uses geographic location information and technical information such as device OS, browser, etc. from Google analytics. No personal information is collected in this process. All such information collected by Google analytics application system may be collated by the DigiLocker only for the purpose of analysis only. 
  15. In case of any grievance, you may send your complaints for redressal to: _support[at]digitallocker[dot]gov[dot]in_
